<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>gbradhopkins.com</title>
    <description>An assortment of tutorials and thoughts on computers, web design and how the internet impacts us all.
</description>
    <link>http://gbradhopkins.com/</link>
    <atom:link href="http://gbradhopkins.com/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/>
    <pubDate>Mon, 14 Nov 2016 23:29:43 -0500</pubDate>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 14 Nov 2016 23:29:43 -0500</lastBuildDate>
    <generator>Jekyll v3.3.0</generator>
    
      <item>
        <title>Working with Ricoh Theta S VR Footage</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;The process for working with Ricoh Theta S VR files requires a couple intermediate steps before you can import the footage into Premiere. I can’t speak to any other editing software but I would expect it to be the case for others as well.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;what-is-vr-and-why-should-i-care&quot;&gt;What is VR and why should I care?&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’m guessing that since you are here, you probably know what VR is and are looking for the answer to a specific question. If that’s the case. You can skip this intro section and get right to the article.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For those that don’t know what VR is, here is a brief explanation.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;VR stands for &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Virtual_reality&quot;&gt;Virtual Reality&lt;/a&gt;. You may have seen ads for VR headsets, in which people with giant headsets grasp at thin air and talk about how amazing it is. For the purposes of this article, we’re going to talk about VR as 360 degree video. Consumer priced camera’s like the &lt;a href=&quot;http://amzn.to/2fABZfS&quot;&gt;Ricoh Theta S&lt;/a&gt; can record 360 degrees of footage, allowing you to pan around as the video is playing. You can also pause the video and pan around to look at some specific item or area that has been captured. It’s really pretty interesting. Best of all, you don’t need a special headset. Most VR can be viewed using your smartphone (especially when uploaded to YouTube), allowing you to pan around by simply changing the direction that your phone is facing.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here is a rough, sample video of a &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=K508tGvjkEs&quot;&gt;walkthrough of my office&lt;/a&gt;, that I created with the Ricoh Theta S. To view the video in VR you must use a supported browser - Chrome or Firefox. Or, you can use your mobile device and the YouTube app.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;style&gt;.embed-container { position: relative; padding-bottom: 56.25%; height: 0; overflow: hidden; max-width: 100%; } .embed-container iframe, .embed-container object, .embed-container embed { position: absolute; top: 0; left: 0; width: 100%; height: 100%; }&lt;/style&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;embed-container&quot;&gt;&lt;iframe src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed//K508tGvjkEs&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Finally, if you want to use a headset, try a &lt;a href=&quot;http://amzn.to/2fPhdK8&quot;&gt;Google Cardboard compatible headset&lt;/a&gt;. They are pretty cheap and allow you to get a good idea for what VR is all about.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Now that we know what VR is. It’s time to get started.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;getting-the-files-off-the-camera&quot;&gt;Getting the files off the camera&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Using the Theta S mobile app, you can save your VR files directly to your device (iPhone or iPad) and then import them using the Photos app. I prefer to connect the Ricoh camera to my Mac and import them using the Image Capture app. This seems like a more straightforward process to me. The camera doesn’t mount on the desktop when plugged into the Mac, like a GoPro or other camera would, so we need to use the Image Capture app where the camera will show up in your list of devices. Once it shows up, you can then import the files to the location of your choice.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you try to use the imported files as-is they will show up as two spherical images side by side.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/vr-spherical-images.png&quot; alt=&quot;Screen capture of spherical images&quot; title=&quot;Screen capture of video directly from the Ricoh Theta S&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Not what we want. So begins the process of converting - processing - and injecting our files to make them usable.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Before importing into our video editor, we need to convert the files. We can do this using the &lt;a href=&quot;https://theta360.com/en/support/download/&quot;&gt;Ricoh Theta app&lt;/a&gt;. There are a number of apps available on the download page, including a live streaming app and the mobile apps. We will be using the “&lt;a href=&quot;https://theta360.com/en/about/application/pc.html&quot;&gt;Basic App&lt;/a&gt;.” &lt;em&gt;I was somewhat surprised to find that the Basic App was an Adobe AIR application. I’m not sure why that surprised me. I guess it’s because I hadn’t seen an Adobe AIR app in a while.&lt;/em&gt; So, if you don’t have Adobe AIR installed, you will be prompted to download and install that before proceeding.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;top-and-bottom-orientation-correction&quot;&gt;Top and Bottom Orientation Correction?&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In addition to converting the files to a format that can be edited in Premiere, the app also corrects top and bottom orientation in your VR files. Whether you are working with VR files in Premiere or simply uploading to YouTube, you will want to correct the orientation. As I worked through how to prepare files for Premiere, I went through a process of trial and error and was surprised to see that the orientation was incorrect when I uploaded my first VR file to YouTube. Initially, I thought it was a problem with the camera. Then I realized that this needed to be corrected using the Ricoh software.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;As a side note, if you are uploading directly to YouTube, Ricoh provides instructions for an &lt;a href=&quot;https://theta360.com/en/howto-youtube/&quot;&gt;upload to YouTube workflow&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;conversion-process&quot;&gt;Conversion Process&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The conversion process is pretty straightforward. Open the Theta App and drop the files that you want to convert on to the main window. You will then be able to select the location to save the converted file, provide a new name and enable top / bottom correction. Depending on the size of the files to be converted, the process can take a while.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For comparison, I have uploaded a raw file from the Ricoh camera and a converted file to YouTube.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://youtu.be/TTKe1Im5Gy4&quot;&gt;Raw File from Ricoh Theta S&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;style&gt;.embed-container { position: relative; padding-bottom: 56.25%; height: 0; overflow: hidden; max-width: 100%; } .embed-container iframe, .embed-container object, .embed-container embed { position: absolute; top: 0; left: 0; width: 100%; height: 100%; }&lt;/style&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;embed-container&quot;&gt;&lt;iframe src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed//TTKe1Im5Gy4&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=25WfsXS3Ofc&quot;&gt;File converted with Ricoh App&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;style&gt;.embed-container { position: relative; padding-bottom: 56.25%; height: 0; overflow: hidden; max-width: 100%; } .embed-container iframe, .embed-container object, .embed-container embed { position: absolute; top: 0; left: 0; width: 100%; height: 100%; }&lt;/style&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;embed-container&quot;&gt;&lt;iframe src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/25WfsXS3Ofc&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As you can see, the file converted with the Ricoh App is the only one that displays properly.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;importing-into-premiere-finally&quot;&gt;Importing into Premiere (Finally)&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Once the file is converted, you are ready to import it into Premiere and start editing. Editing a VR clip in Premiere is basically the same as with a non-VR video clip. To make previewing your VR content more natural, you will want to enable VR Video display in either the Program or Source monitor. This allows you to pan around your VR the way you would when viewing the video on YouTube. You can read more about this in the &lt;a href=&quot;https://helpx.adobe.com/premiere-pro/kb/work-with-vr.html&quot;&gt;Working with immersive VR video&lt;/a&gt; article on the Adobe Help site.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;exporting-from-premiere&quot;&gt;Exporting from Premiere&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Once you have finished editing your video in Premiere, the export process is largely unchanged. If you scroll through the settings, you will notice that there is a VR checkbox which should be ticked. Adobe also recommends that you select “Stretch to Fill” in the Source Scaling option.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;Regardless of the Format and Preset you select, be certain to change the Source Scaling option in the Export Settings dialog box to Stretch To Fill. If you don’t change this option, you are likely to introduce either letterbox or pillars to the exported video, which breaks the seam of the sphere and distorts it. &lt;a href=&quot;https://helpx.adobe.com/premiere-pro/kb/work-with-vr.html&quot;&gt;- Working with immersive VR video&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As you can see in the video below, I didn’t use the “Stretch to Fill” option and there is a hole (black area) in the video if you pan down as if looking at the floor..&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;style&gt;.embed-container { position: relative; padding-bottom: 56.25%; height: 0; overflow: hidden; max-width: 100%; } .embed-container iframe, .embed-container object, .embed-container embed { position: absolute; top: 0; left: 0; width: 100%; height: 100%; }&lt;/style&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;embed-container&quot;&gt;&lt;iframe src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/EJUzrqhfe2g&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Once you change those settings, export the file.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;injecting-meta-data&quot;&gt;Injecting Meta Data&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Now that we have the exported file from Premiere, we have one final step which requires another app, this one called &lt;a href=&quot;https://support.google.com/jump/answer/7044297?hl=en&quot;&gt;Spatial Media Metadata Injector&lt;/a&gt; which adds metadata to the file allowing YouTube to recognize it as a spherical file.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Again, this app is very straightforward. Simply open the app, select the file, tick the “My video is spherical (360)” checkbox and hit “Inject metadata.” Once the app finishes, you are now ready to upload the app to YouTube. Once the video has been uploaded to YouTube you can use your web browser (currently Chrome and Firefox are compatible with YouTube VR videos), phone (YouTube app) or a VR Viewer like Google Cardboard to explore the VR video.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Obviously, it would be a lot easier if you didn’t have to run your video file through multiple apps to prep it for viewing. I would assume that as the VR format matures and becomes more mainstream, tools like Premiere will do a better job of handling all of these steps. In the mean time, it’s a small price to pay for such an interesting technology.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 14 Nov 2016 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>http://gbradhopkins.com/vr/2016/11/14/working-with-ricoh-theta-s-vr-footage.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://gbradhopkins.com/vr/2016/11/14/working-with-ricoh-theta-s-vr-footage.html</guid>
        
        
        <category>vr</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>The One Feature That Keeps Me On Evernote</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;I’m a big fan of Evernote. So much so, that in &lt;a href=&quot;http://firebrand.media/blog/article/why_i_write_in_evernote&quot;&gt;a previous entry on my business blog&lt;/a&gt;, I outlined the reasons that I thought Evernote was the best software for writing (among other things).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But, Evernote has made some changes (as software companies have a tendency to do), the most concerning of which is the &lt;a href=&quot;https://help.evernote.com/hc/en-us/articles/226885427-FAQ-About-Migration-to-Google-Cloud-Platform&quot;&gt;migration of data to the Google Cloud Platform&lt;/a&gt;. Say what you will about the advantages of the cloud, in the end it boils down to the fact that my data is on someone else’s computer. It is not lost on me that this was always the case. But, now we’ve got another layer of separation between me and my data. So, instead of relying on someone else, I’d like to own and control as much of my data as possible.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;With that in mind, I’ve started to explore alternative solutions for many of the cloud based products that I use. As always, the question is, “Does the alternative solution have a practical workflow?” Is it something I can use reliably? The next most important question is “Have I become so reliant on a particular aspect of the current service - in this case Evernote - that it is impractical to change the way I work?”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;ds-note-an-alternative-to-evernote&quot;&gt;DS Note, an Alternative to Evernote&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Evernote alternative that I am testing is DS Note, a package of the &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.synology.com/en-us/dsm/6.0/features&quot;&gt;Synology DiskStation&lt;/a&gt; that I have installed on my &lt;a href=&quot;https://iosafe.com/products-216nas-overview&quot;&gt;ioSafe&lt;/a&gt; Network Attached Server (NAS). The ioSafe is a water &lt;em&gt;and&lt;/em&gt; fire proof NAS. Primarily, I have been using it to automatically back up photos from my phones (both iOS and Android) using the DS Photo package. To a lesser extent, I am also using it to store files, a la Dropbox, using the Cloudstation package. There are &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.synology.com/en-us/dsm/app_packages/all_app&quot;&gt;a number of packages available&lt;/a&gt;, most with corresponding mobile apps. In fact, if my workflow didn’t include a desktop computer, the one key feature that is keeping me with Evernote would probably be solved.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;one-key-feature---email-to-evernote&quot;&gt;One Key Feature - Email to Evernote&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is it. The deal breaker. With all &lt;a href=&quot;https://evernote.com/upgrade/?tier=plus&quot;&gt;paid Evernote accounts&lt;/a&gt;, you get a custom email address allowing you to forward email messages to your account. You can even file them to a specific notebook by adding @notebook-name to the end of the subject line. This has been a huge timesaver for me, as one of my primary uses of Evernote is to store business receipts. Most receipts are in the form of an email which I simply annotate with whatever reference info I need and then forward it to the @receipts notebook in Evernote.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There is no feature like this for DS Note.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;close-but-no-cigar&quot;&gt;Close but no cigar&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In the open, I mentioned that if my workflow didn’t include the desktop I may be able to make DS Note work. With the DS Note mobile app installed on a device, DS Note is an option in any share sheet (see image below). This allows me to create a new note from any email - taking place of the “Email to Evernote” feature that is such a deal breaker for me. It would mean a change in how I work because I’d need to manage any emails that I want to save as notes through a mobile device. I’ve started testing this to see if it is a workable solution. We’ll see.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/DS-Note-share-sheet.PNG&quot; alt=&quot;DS Note in the Spark Email share sheet&quot; title=&quot;DS Note in the Spark Email share sheet&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;final-thoughts&quot;&gt;Final Thoughts&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’m sure there are other Evernote features that have no counterpart in DS Note including &lt;a href=&quot;https://evernote.com/webclipper/&quot;&gt;web clipper&lt;/a&gt; (although, if you’re a Chrome user - I’m not - then you’re in luck because there is a &lt;a href=&quot;https://chrome.google.com/webstore/detail/synology-web-clipper/pcfbfimijgibligmbglggnbiobgjgmbk&quot;&gt;Synology Web Clipper app&lt;/a&gt; for Chrome), search for text in images, pdfs and handwritten notes, and &lt;a href=&quot;https://blog.evernote.com/blog/2014/05/14/meetings-done-right/&quot;&gt;presentation mode&lt;/a&gt; which I’ve found handy at times. Personally, none of these are deal breakers the way that Email to Evernote is for me.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I like the idea of having control of all of my data but if it’s too difficult to actually manage the data, what’s the point?&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Sat, 12 Nov 2016 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>http://gbradhopkins.com/software/2016/11/12/why-I-cant-switch-to-ds-note-from-evernote.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://gbradhopkins.com/software/2016/11/12/why-I-cant-switch-to-ds-note-from-evernote.html</guid>
        
        
        <category>software</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Moving gbradhopkins.com from ExpressionEngine to Jekyll</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Looking for an opportunity to play around with Git, Markdown and Jekyll, I have decided to move &lt;a href=&quot;http://gbradhopkins.com&quot;&gt;this site&lt;/a&gt; from &lt;a href=&quot;http://ellislab.com/expressionengine&quot;&gt;ExpressionEngine (EECMS)&lt;/a&gt; - which I love and use on most projects - to &lt;a href=&quot;http://jekyllrb.com&quot;&gt;Jekyll&lt;/a&gt;, a static site generator.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;static-site-generator&quot;&gt;Static Site Generator?&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;What is a static site generator and why would you want to use it?&lt;/em&gt; I’m glad you asked.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A static site generator takes a template directory containing raw text files in various formats, runs it through a converter and a renderer, and spits out a complete, ready-to-publish static website suitable for serving with your favorite web server, or even for free using Github Pages (more on that later).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A static website doesn’t require a database, which can increase security and will typically load faster. &lt;em&gt;Although, there are plenty of ways to slow down a static site.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In addition to increased security and speed, Jekyll also creates a local server for testing purposes. Every time you make a change to a file or post, you can preview the change locally before pushing the site live. This is a great time saver, especially when testing a responsive design or a blog post.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Finally, if you are using Jekyll, and have a Github account, you can host your site for free using &lt;a href=&quot;https://pages.github.com&quot;&gt;Github Pages&lt;/a&gt;. You can even use your own domain - as I’m doing here.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Of course, there are some restrictions, one being that many of the Jekyll plugins that are available can’t be used because Github runs Jekyll in safe mode. Another restriction that I found is the lack of a .htaccess file, meaning that I couldn’t redirect my pages from their old URL to their new URL. One way that I tried to overcome this was by creating a sitemap and submitting it to Google, using the Google Search Console (formerly Webmaster Tools).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;caveat&quot;&gt;Caveat&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Besides the restrictions mentioned above, there is another major caveat regarding the usage of Jekyll.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The Command Line&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Back in 2015, &lt;a href=&quot;http://epwebtech.com/events/2015/08/12/getting-started-with-jekyll.html&quot;&gt;I gave a talk on creating websites with Jekyll.&lt;/a&gt; My first caveat was that you need to use the terminal / command line interface (CLI). I knew that would be a dealbreaker for some people but, if you can overcome your fear of the terminal, using Jekyll can help make you more comfortable with a CLI.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Now that we’ve got the why and why not out of the way, let’s get started.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;installing-jekyll-on-a-mac&quot;&gt;Installing Jekyll on a Mac&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For the full installation guide, &lt;a href=&quot;https://jekyllrb.com/docs/installation/&quot;&gt;check out the Jekyll install documentation&lt;/a&gt;. Here is my quick overview.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;First make sure that you have &lt;a href=&quot;https://itunes.apple.com/us/app/xcode/id497799835&quot;&gt;Xcode&lt;/a&gt; installed. It’s a free download from the app store.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Using the terminal / command line, run the following command to install Jekyll.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;gem install jekyll&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you run into an error, first make sure that you have Xcode installed. If Xcode is installed, try installing Jekyll again with this command (which will require that you supply the password for your computer).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;sudo gem install jekyll&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If everything goes well, Jekyll will now be installed on your computer and you can start using it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’m not going to get into the ‘how’ of designing a site with Jekyll. That may be a later blog entry but for now I’m more concerned with the transition from ExpressionEngine to Jekyll.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;bulk-entry-export&quot;&gt;Bulk Entry Export&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In addition to creating a blog in Jekyll, I wanted to move all/some of my posts from EECMS.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’ll admit, what follows is a bit of a cheat. I wanted to export my entries from EECMS to Jekyll but I just couldn’t figure out how without putting in a bunch of time that I didn’t have. So, instead, I came up with the following solution that I used to export &lt;em&gt;ALL&lt;/em&gt; of my entries from EECMS to a single HTML file. This file exports each entry as a field in a table. Because most of my entries were old and no longer relevant, I was satisfied to use this as more of a time capsule, or archive, so that in the future I can look back at what I wrote.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;&lt;pre class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;code&gt;&amp;lt;?php
    header(&quot;Content-type: application/vnd.ms-excel&quot;);
header(&quot;Content-Disposition: attachment; filename=gbradhopkins-entries-exports.xls&quot;);
header(&quot;Pragma: no-cache&quot;);
header(&quot;Expires: 0&quot;);
?&amp;gt;
&amp;lt;table&amp;gt;
&amp;lt;tbody&amp;gt;
{exp:channel:entries channel='tutorials' limit='500' disable=&quot;categories|member_data|pagination|trackbacks&quot;}
    &amp;lt;tr&amp;gt;
	    &amp;lt;td valign=&quot;top&quot;&amp;gt;{title}&amp;lt;/td&amp;gt;
            &amp;lt;td&amp;gt;{tutorial_body}&amp;lt;/td&amp;gt;&amp;lt;td&amp;gt;{tutorial_image}&amp;lt;/td&amp;gt;&amp;lt;td&amp;gt;{tutorial_hero_image}&amp;lt;/td&amp;gt;
    &amp;lt;/tr&amp;gt;
{/exp:channel:entries}
&amp;lt;/tbody&amp;gt;
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;exporting-individual-entries&quot;&gt;Exporting Individual Entries&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For most, exporting a single file that includes every entry is probably not practical and, honestly if I could figure it out, I wanted to maintain the entries as individual files as well.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The thing I love most about ExpressionEngine is the ability to format and display your data however you need. Using two templates I was able to:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;List all of my entries with the naming convention that Jekyll requires - “Year-Month-Day-Title.md” - I was set on using Markdown so the .md format was important.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Click a link to download each entry formatted for Jekyll with the &lt;a href=&quot;https://pages.github.com&quot;&gt;front matter&lt;/a&gt; already in place - layout, title, categories, date, custom image field for hero images.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;List of Entries Template&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is a very simple template but it gets the job done, creating a list of entries with links to download the individual files.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;&lt;pre class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;code&gt;&amp;lt;ul&amp;gt;
{exp:channel:entries channel=&quot;tutorials|reviews&quot; dynamic=&quot;off&quot; disable=&quot;member_data|pagination&quot;}
&amp;lt;li&amp;gt;&amp;lt;a href=&quot;{title_permalink='exports/post'}&quot; target=&quot;blank&quot;&amp;gt;{entry_date format='%Y-%m-%d'}-{url_title}.md&amp;lt;/a&amp;gt;&amp;lt;/li&amp;gt;
{/exp:channel:entries}
&amp;lt;/ul&amp;gt;
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Entry Download Template&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Clicking on the entry link from the list above, fires the template below which initiates the download process. If you are trying to use this template, make sure you turn on ‘Allow PHP’ in the template preferences in EE.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;&lt;pre class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;code&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;{&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;err&quot;&gt;exp:channel:entries&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;w&quot;&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;err&quot;&gt;channel=&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;nt&quot;&gt;&quot;tutorials|reviews&quot;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;w&quot;&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;err&quot;&gt;disable=&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;nt&quot;&gt;&quot;member_data|pagination&quot;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;err&quot;&gt;}&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;w&quot;&gt;
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;err&quot;&gt;&amp;lt;?php&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;w&quot;&gt;
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;err&quot;&gt;header(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;s2&quot;&gt;&quot;Content-type: text/markdown; charset=UTF-8&quot;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;err&quot;&gt;);&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;w&quot;&gt;
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;err&quot;&gt;header(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;s2&quot;&gt;&quot;Content-Disposition: attachment; filename={entry_date format='%Y-%m-%d'}-{url_title}.md&quot;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;err&quot;&gt;);&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;w&quot;&gt;
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;err&quot;&gt;header(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;s2&quot;&gt;&quot;Pragma: no-cache&quot;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;err&quot;&gt;);&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;w&quot;&gt;
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;err&quot;&gt;header(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;s2&quot;&gt;&quot;Expires: 0&quot;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;err&quot;&gt;);&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;w&quot;&gt;
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;err&quot;&gt;?&amp;gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;w&quot;&gt;
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;err&quot;&gt;---&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;w&quot;&gt;
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;err&quot;&gt;layout:&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;w&quot;&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;err&quot;&gt;post&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;w&quot;&gt;
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;err&quot;&gt;title:&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;w&quot;&gt;  &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;s2&quot;&gt;&quot;{title}&quot;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;w&quot;&gt;
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;err&quot;&gt;date:&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;w&quot;&gt;   &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;{&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;err&quot;&gt;entry_date&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;w&quot;&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;err&quot;&gt;format='%Y-%m-%d&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;w&quot;&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;err&quot;&gt;%H-%i-%s'&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;}&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;w&quot;&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;mi&quot;&gt;-0500&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;w&quot;&gt;
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;err&quot;&gt;categories:&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;w&quot;&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;{&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;err&quot;&gt;categories&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;}{&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;err&quot;&gt;category_name&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;}{&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;err&quot;&gt;/categories&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;}&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;w&quot;&gt;
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;{&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;err&quot;&gt;if&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;w&quot;&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;err&quot;&gt;tutorial_hero_image&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;}&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;err&quot;&gt;image:&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;w&quot;&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;{&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;err&quot;&gt;tutorial_hero_image&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;}{&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;err&quot;&gt;/if&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;}&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;w&quot;&gt;
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;{&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;err&quot;&gt;if&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;w&quot;&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;err&quot;&gt;review_hero_image&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;}&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;err&quot;&gt;image:&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;w&quot;&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;{&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;err&quot;&gt;review_hero_image&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;}{&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;err&quot;&gt;/if&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;}&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;w&quot;&gt;
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;err&quot;&gt;---&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;w&quot;&gt;

&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;{&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;err&quot;&gt;exp:marker:tomarkdown&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;}&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;w&quot;&gt;
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;{&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;err&quot;&gt;tutorial_hero_image&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;}&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;w&quot;&gt;

&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;{&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;err&quot;&gt;tutorial_body&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;}&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;w&quot;&gt;

&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;{&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;err&quot;&gt;tutorial_image&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;}&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;w&quot;&gt;

&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;{&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;err&quot;&gt;review_body&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;}&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;w&quot;&gt;
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;{&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;err&quot;&gt;/exp:marker:tomarkdown&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;}&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;w&quot;&gt;

&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;{&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;err&quot;&gt;/exp:channel:entries&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;}&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;w&quot;&gt;
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The one thing I couldn’t figure out was how to download the file with the .md file extension. Using the above code downloads a file with .md.html as the file extension. I simply used a renaming app to batch rename all of the files to .md.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I then dropped the files in my _posts directory, rebuilt my site and pushed the changes to my Github account.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;one-more-thing&quot;&gt;One More Thing…&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Remember to run &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;jekyll build&lt;/code&gt; after you make changes to your site. Whether it be a post, config file, css file… whatever. This command rebuilds your site and all changes are made and regenerated to the static site files found in the _site directory.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Remember, &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;jekyll build&lt;/code&gt; and then push the site to Git, your server… wherever.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;links-of-note&quot;&gt;Links of note&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://expressionengine.stackexchange.com/questions/515/what-is-the-best-method-for-exporting-channel-entries-as-a-spreadsheet&quot;&gt;Exporting entries from EECMS to an HTML file&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://devot-ee.com/add-ons/marker&quot;&gt;Marker Add-on for EECMS to convert entries to Markdown&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://milanaryal.com/writing-and-formatting-with-markdown/&quot;&gt;Formatting Markdown in Jekyll&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://gitref.org/basic/#add&quot;&gt;Git Reference Guide&lt;/a&gt; - Basics of commiting and pushing content.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://epwebtech.com/blog/2015/08/17/jekyll-resources-and-links.html&quot;&gt;Jekyll Links and Resources&lt;/a&gt; - A list of resources that I pulled together for a talk that I gave back in 2015.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://epwebtech.com/blog/2015/08/18/publishing-site-to-github.html&quot;&gt;Publishing a Jekyll Site on Gituhub&lt;/a&gt; - Notes on publishing a Jekyll site on Github from the same talk.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://reyhan.org/2013/03/jekyll-archive-without-plugins.html&quot;&gt;Creating Jekyll Archives with using Plugins&lt;/a&gt; - A great snippet of code that allows you to list your entires by year and date. You can view &lt;a href=&quot;http://gbradhopkins.com/archive.html&quot;&gt;my site archives template&lt;/a&gt; that is based on this code.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Fri, 04 Nov 2016 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
        <link>http://gbradhopkins.com/web/design/tutorials/2016/11/04/switching-to-jekyll-from-ee.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://gbradhopkins.com/web/design/tutorials/2016/11/04/switching-to-jekyll-from-ee.html</guid>
        
        
        <category>Web</category>
        
        <category>Design</category>
        
        <category>Tutorials</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Basic Git Commands</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Generally, I don’t use the command line to interact with my version controlled client accounts. In most cases, I prefer to use &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.git-tower.com&quot;&gt;Tower&lt;/a&gt;, a great Git client for Mac and Windows but in the case of gbradhopkins.com, I decided to use the command line as a way of becoming more familiar with it. Below are the basic commands that I use to push content to my Github account.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;These are the steps for commiting new or updated content to my &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/firebrandmedia&quot;&gt;Github account&lt;/a&gt;. As I use Git more, hopefully these will become muscle memory and I’ll no longer need this document. Until then…&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;commands-for-pushing-content&quot;&gt;Commands for pushing content&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After creating or editing a file, run the following commands in the Terminal.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;git status&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is an optional command. It simply shows what has changed and results in something like this:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;&lt;pre class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;code&gt;modified:   _includes/head.html
modified:   _sass/_gbradhopkins.scss
modified:   css/main.scss
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We can then review the list of changes and if satisfied, move to the next step.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;git add .&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;git commit -m 'Commit message here'&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After adding our commit message and hitting enter, we receive a message indicating what we’ve done (or are about to do).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;
[gh-pages c5656de] git article update
 1 file changed, 3 insertions(+), 1 deletion(-)
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;git push &lt;/code&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;That’s it. All done. The files are now commited to the repository that we’ve been working in.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Next up, how to access that repository from another computer to continue working on it.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Thu, 29 Sep 2016 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
        <link>http://gbradhopkins.com/web/design/tutorials/2016/09/29/git-commit-workflow.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://gbradhopkins.com/web/design/tutorials/2016/09/29/git-commit-workflow.html</guid>
        
        
        <category>Web</category>
        
        <category>Design</category>
        
        <category>Tutorials</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Ripping a DVD to iPod Video on Windows XP</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Update - 7/03/13 - &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.macworld.com/article/1157590/how_to_rip_dvd_handbrake.html&quot;&gt;Macworld decided to one up me and provided their own, in-depth instruction guide on how to rip a DVD with handbrake. They go into a lot more detail than I did. Read mine first, and then, if you still can’t figure it out or need more help, check out their guide.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If like me, you still have an iPod Video around, you may decide that you want to use it to store movies for when you travel, after all, you can hook it up to a TV using the video out cable so it makes a pretty good movie storage device.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;enter-handbrake&quot;&gt;Enter Handbrake&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“HandBrake is a tool for converting video from nearly any format to a selection of modern, widely supported codecs.” Best of all, it’s free.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://handbrake.fr/&quot;&gt;Handbrake&lt;/a&gt; has a &lt;a href=&quot;http://handbrake.fr/features.php&quot;&gt;number of features&lt;/a&gt; that you can use to tweak your video to your liking and export in the format that you need. In addition to the ability to specify your export settings, Handbrake has a number of built in pre-sets that allow for one-click setting of the export. Primarily, I use Handbrake to rip DVDs which I play through my AppleTV so I just use the appropriate AppleTV export preset.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;using-handbrake&quot;&gt;Using Handbrake&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In the following steps, I’m going to show you how to export video for iPod Video and then add it to iTunes but it’s basically the same for any Apple device (iPhone, iPod Touch, AppleTV).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;First, you need to download and install Handbrake. This will also install the .NET framework if it is not already installed.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Once Handbrake is installed, the process is pretty straightforward.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Select the Preset.&lt;/strong&gt; Select iPod (or whichever your destination device is). If you select iPod, make sure that iPod 5G Support is enabled via the Output Settings checkbox.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/Handbrake_Step_1.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Step 1&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Select the Source.&lt;/strong&gt; Click on the source icon, and then select Open Folder. You will now browse My Computer and find the name of the DVD in the device list. In the screenshot below, I selected the DVD, A Bugs Life to rip and then click on OK.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Handbrake will then scan the source for the video to be ripped.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/Handbrake_Step_2.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Step 2&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Next, give the file a name - ie. A Bugs Life&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/Handbrake_Step_3.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Step 3&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Finally, click on the Start button.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/Handbrake_Step_4.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Step 4&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Handbrake will now rip the DVD to the desktop.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Once Handbrake has completed the encoding process, the file will be on your desktop - or the destination location that you selected. Once ripped, using the iPod 5G settings, the .MP4 file is around 542MB.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Now, you can drag the .MP4 file into your iTunes library.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/iTunes_Step_1.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;iTunes Step 1&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You may notice that the movie is not showing up in your Movies directory in iTunes. That’s because the video that was exported is categorized as a “Home Video” so it is found in the Home Videos directory.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To change this, right click on the movie and select “Get Info.” &lt;em&gt;I’m doing this on a Mac so I’m not sure what it is on Windows but I would guess that it is similar.&lt;/em&gt; Under “Media Kind” select Movie instead of Home Video.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/iTunes_Step_2.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;iTunes Step 2&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Now, your ripped video will should be displayed under Movies.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/iTunes_Step_3.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;iTunes Step 3&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Finally, go into the settings for your iPod and select the check box next to the movie to indicate that it should be synched to your device. Now, hit “Apply” and the movie will be synched to the iPod.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/iTunes_Step_4.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;iTunes Step 4&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
        <pubDate>Tue, 25 Jun 2013 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
        <link>http://gbradhopkins.com/pc/tutorials/2013/06/25/ripping-dvd-to-ipod-video.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://gbradhopkins.com/pc/tutorials/2013/06/25/ripping-dvd-to-ipod-video.html</guid>
        
        
        <category>PC</category>
        
        <category>Tutorials</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>I really want to like you Flickr</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;I’m a big fan of Flickr. Or, at least I was. If I had to describe our relationship I would describe it as complicated. I’m not a huge fan of the new layout but I can live with it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/Flickr-Bar.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Yahoo! Universal Header&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What I can’t live with is the new Yahoo! toolbar that I’m seeing on one of my Flickr accounts - highlighted in red in the image above. This is a premium account. I paid for it. Even when the distinguishing features - namely, lots of space - were added to the standard account, I didn’t downgrade it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Another feature of a premium account was the fact that there are no ads. I consider this an ad. It’s not adding to my experience. It’s pushing other Yahoo! services and links. I don’t need that.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So far, I’m only seeing this on one of my accounts so I’ll monitor it and see where it goes. Needless to say, I don’t like the direction that it’s heading.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For further reading, check out some of the Flickr Forum discussions on the new “Yahoo! Universal Header”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.flickr.com/help/forum/en-us/72157633459717740/&quot;&gt;http://www.flickr.com/help/forum/en-us/72157633459717740/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.flickr.com/help/forum/en-us/72157633201655378/&quot;&gt;http://www.flickr.com/help/forum/en-us/72157633201655378/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Thu, 13 Jun 2013 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
        <link>http://gbradhopkins.com/tech-annoyances/2013/06/13/i-really-want-to-like-you-flickr.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://gbradhopkins.com/tech-annoyances/2013/06/13/i-really-want-to-like-you-flickr.html</guid>
        
        
        <category>tech-annoyances</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Get Fit and Help Those In Need</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Generally speaking, getting in shape is a selfish endeavor. We usually try to get in shape because we want to look better or feel better about ourselves. I mean, we could say we’re doing it for our kids or for our loved ones but if we’re honest, it’s mostly about self-image. I don’t think there’s anything inherently wrong with that, although we can become obsessed with it and let vanity rule our lives, but let’s just assume that we’re not taking it that far.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://gbradhopkins.com/images/uploads/tutorials/charity_miles.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Charity Miles image&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What if, in addition to trying to get in shape for our own selfish reasons, we could also help someone in need? That’s the concept behind &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.charitymiles.org/&quot;&gt;Charity Miles&lt;/a&gt;. Charity Miles allows you to earn money for charity when you walk, run, or bike.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I first heard about Charity Miles at South by Southwest. I participated in the daily Brooks Cowboy Run and someone handed me a postcard on my way back to my hotel following a run. If you’ve ever been to SxSW before, then you know that you are inundated with people trying to get you to check out their new app, product or service. So, I stuffed the postcard in my bag when I got back to my hotel and forgot about it. Last week, I was cleaning out my bag in preparation for a meeting and I found the postcard. I decided to check out Charity Miles, so I downloaded the app and checked out the website.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;How does it work?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;From the Charity Miles website: “Ready to become a sponsored athlete? Simply turn on the app, choose a charity, and press start. As you exercise, we’ll track your distance and the money earned. When you’re finished, accept your sponsorship, spread the word, and we’ll send you a note confirming your good work. It’s as easy as this: get moving. Bikers earn 10¢ a mile and walkers and runners earn 25¢ a mile, up to our initial $1,000,000 sponsorship pool.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As a dedicated Nike+ user, my typical running routine is to either use the Nike+ app on my phone or use the Nike+ app on my iPod touch in conjunction with the Zombies, Run! app. So, instead of using the Nike+ app or the Zombies, Run! app, I have started to use the Charity Miles app in conjunction with my iPod touch. (I’ve got to keep logging those Nike+ miles!)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;For me, the best feature is the ability to see the direct impact of each run, walk or bike… my 2.361 mile run with Feeding America selected as the charity accounted for 4.72 meals to hungry people.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So far, my experience with the Charity Miles app has been pretty good, although, the first time I used it it crashed and I lost my run. Not a good way to start - especially since it was a 4 mile run. Since that first experience, the app has been solid and I’ve been able to see the value in using the app as a way to help charitable organizations without any extra effort on my part.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Current organizations include:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;VisionSpring&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;every mother counts&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Feeding America&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Autism Speaks&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Wounded Warrior Project&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Stand Up To Cancer&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Achilles International&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;The Michael J. Fox Foundation&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Red&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;World Food Programme&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;The Nature Conservancy&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;ASPCA&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Habitat for Humanity&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Leukemia &amp;amp; Lymphoma Society&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Partnership for a Healthier America&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Pencils of Promise&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Girl Up&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Shot @ Life&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;NothingButNets.net&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;IronMan Foundation&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;DoSomething.org&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As you can see, whether you want to help out here in the US or internationally, there are plenty of charities to choose from.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For me, the best feature is the ability to see the direct impact of each run, walk or bike. In addition to showing how long or how far you ran, there is an impact screen that shows the direct impact of your workout. For example, my 2.361 mile run with Feeding America selected as the charity accounted for 4.72 meals to hungry people while my 1.775 mile run with Habitat for Humanity as the selected charity accounted for 4.44 pieces of lumber.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;At the end of each run, you also have the chance to share your run via Twitter or Facebook, sharing your run with not only your friends, but also the organization that you supported.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;I ran 1.775 @&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/charitymiles&quot;&gt;charitymiles&lt;/a&gt; for @&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/habitat_org&quot;&gt;habitat_org&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/search/%23EveryMileMatters&quot;&gt;#EveryMileMatters&lt;/a&gt;— Brad Hopkins (@gbradhopkins)&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/gbradhopkins/status/335203585304440832&quot;&gt;May 17, 2013&lt;/a&gt;
So, are you looking for a little extra motivation? Tired of running from zombies? I’d recommend giving the &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.charitymiles.org/&quot;&gt;Charity Miles&lt;/a&gt; app a try. It’s available for iOS and Android.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

</description>
        <pubDate>Fri, 17 May 2013 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
        <link>http://gbradhopkins.com/internet/tutorials/2013/05/17/get-fit-and-help-those-in-need.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://gbradhopkins.com/internet/tutorials/2013/05/17/get-fit-and-help-those-in-need.html</guid>
        
        
        <category>Internet</category>
        
        <category>Tutorials</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Review: GIF Brewery</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;GIFs are everywhere. I remember building animated GIFs frame by frame in Photoshop using that timeline at the bottom of the screen and hating every minute of it. Now, it has become some sort of art form? How did this happen? Apps, I guess. And, faster internet. Oh well, who am I to reject a novel art form?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Looking (well, not actually looking) for a way to to create GIFs, I stumbled upon &lt;a href=&quot;http://gifbrewery.com/&quot;&gt;GIF Brewery&lt;/a&gt;, a $4.99 app (available on the Mac App Store) for converting video to GIFs. Beyond just converting a video clip to a GIF, GIF Brewery allows you to fine tune your GIF by cropping, resizing, adding captions (with start and end times), adjusting colors, applying filters and sharpening the image.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I decided to test out GIF Brewery by converting a video clip from Little League Day at Oriole Park into a GIF. On Little League day, all of the local Little Leagues bring their kids to the ballpark and they parade around the field, high-fiving players and fans. As the coach of my daughter’s team, I was able to parade around with her and record it. The original clip was about 3 minutes long but with GIF Brewery, I was able to trim it down to the 23 seconds when she was walking by the dugout giving high-fives to the Orioles players. This is done by setting Start / End points.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In addition to trimming the video, I also added captions, naming each player that she high-fives. Captions can also be given Start / End points. I then set the GIF duration (Frame Count) to 250 frames and created the GIF. Initially, I was thinking of frame count as frame rate and I set it for 25. That gave me a choppy 25 frame GIF. I quickly realized my error, adjusted the setting to 250 frames and then created it again. In an effort to shrink the file size further, I finally settled on 130 frames which was just enough to not make it look like a turn of the century silent film.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Just for comparison, the original video (1920 x 1080) weighed in at 53MB while the GIF (740 x 417) is 21MB.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For fun, I decided to use to color adjustment tools to create the turn of the century silent film version which weighs in at 9MB.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://gbradhopkins.com/images/uploads/reviews/Abby_High_5s_bw.gif&quot; alt=&quot;Silent Film Version&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The GIF Brewery interface is really straightforward and easy to grasp. Options for captions and GIF properties open in new palettes. Your project can be saved, allowing you to go back to it later and make adjustments.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://gbradhopkins.com/images/uploads/reviews/GIFBrewery_interface.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;GIF Brewery Interface&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;At this time, you can’t build animations frame by frame, it only supports converting video to GIF. Personally, I’m fine with that.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There are some negative reviews in the Mac App store which talk about crashes but I haven’t experienced it. I’ll keep this tool handy. I can see it becoming useful for both work (reviews, product walkthroughs) and fun.&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
        <pubDate>Fri, 10 May 2013 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
        <link>http://gbradhopkins.com/reviews/2013/05/10/gif-brewery.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://gbradhopkins.com/reviews/2013/05/10/gif-brewery.html</guid>
        
        
        <category>Reviews</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Internet Privacy Links</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Internet privacy and the way companies like Facebook, Google and Twitter use our data has been on my mind recently. Here are a collection of links related to those topics. At some point, I’m going to pull it all together and express my feelings on this important topic. For the time being, these are as much for me as they are for anyone finding them here on this page.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://gbradhopkins.com/images/uploads/tutorials/internet_privacy.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Privacy Image&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://fixtracking.com/&quot;&gt;Fix Tracking:&lt;/a&gt; How-to stop getting tracked in your Browser.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://chronicle.com/article/Why-Privacy-Matters-Even-if/127461/&quot;&gt;Why Privacy Matters Even if You Have ‘Nothing to Hide’&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://online.wsj.com/article/SB10001424127887324482504578453223207072376.html?mod=rss_Technology&quot;&gt;Online Ads Can Now Follow You Home&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Photo Credit: &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.flickr.com/photos/doegox/8016617207/sizes/l/in/photostream/&quot;&gt;http://www.flickr.com/photos/doegox/8016617207/sizes/l/in/photostream/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
        <pubDate>Tue, 30 Apr 2013 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
        <link>http://gbradhopkins.com/internet/tutorials/2013/04/30/internet-privacy-links.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://gbradhopkins.com/internet/tutorials/2013/04/30/internet-privacy-links.html</guid>
        
        
        <category>Internet</category>
        
        <category>Tutorials</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>MacHeist nanoBundle 3. $10 well spent.</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;I’ve always been a big fan of the &lt;a href=&quot;http://macheist.com/&quot;&gt;MacHeist&lt;/a&gt; deals. The newest bundle (nanoBundle 3) is a great little bundle of apps for $10. Unfortunately, for me, most of the apps that I would want, I already own.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;./images/MacHeist-Bundle-3.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;MachHeist Bundle Image&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The headliners are Fantastical (normally $20),  xScope ($30) and CleanMyMac 2 ($40). I use Fantastical and xScope all the time and CleanMyMac 2 is a well crafted app that helps get rid of useless files on your Mac.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://flexibits.com/fantastical&quot;&gt;Fantastical&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Fantastical is a great little menu-bar calendar that not only allows you to view your upcoming events, but also allows you to add events to your calendar using natural language. So, instead of filling in a series of form fields to add an event to your calendar, you can type in “Meeting with client at 3PM tomorrow at the coffee shop” and Fantastical will add it to your calendar.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://iconfactory.com/software/xscope&quot;&gt;xScope&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;xScope, from The Iconfactory, is a set of measuring tools geared toward design and development. My favorite tools are the Ruler - a ruler to measure items on-screen, Guides - similar to the guides you can create in Illustrator and Photoshop but instead of limited to a single application, they float above all of your windows allowing you to keep things in alignment no matter what app you are using. I also frequently use Dimensions, a simple measuring tool that automatically measures the space between objects simply by moving your pointer around the screen.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://macpaw.com/cleanmymac&quot;&gt;CleanMyMac 2&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;CleanMyMac is one of those applications that you don’t really think about until you need it. The big benefit of CleanMyMac has always been finding and deleting unnecessary files on your Mac. In version 2, they have added some really useful features like iPhoto Cleanup which optimizes and reduces the size of you photo library by removing unneeded service copies of images, Trash Cleanup which empties all system Trash folders of your Mac’s internal and external drives, and Uninstaller which allows you to select apps to uninstall completely or reset to their initial state. All of this is done in a beautiful interface with a robust help system to help you understand what you are about to do.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In addition to those three apps, which will more than justify the price, the bundle also includes some interesting apps that I am not familiar with but may need to check out - &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.clarify-it.com/&quot;&gt;Clarify&lt;/a&gt; (Clarify makes it easy to create gorgeous tutorials and how-to’s.), &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.airserver.com/&quot;&gt;AirServer&lt;/a&gt; (Beam music and videos from your iPhone or iPad to your Mac!) and Path Finder (If you’ve ever wished that the Finder supported tabs like a web browser, &lt;a href=&quot;http://cocoatech.com/pathfinder/&quot;&gt;Path Finder&lt;/a&gt; is the tool for you.)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In addition to a terrific bundle of apps, &lt;a href=&quot;http://macheist.com/#charity&quot;&gt;10% of your purchase goes to the charity of your choice&lt;/a&gt; (from a list of charities that they have selected).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;All in all, this is a great deal, and I think I’ve talked myself into buying the bundle.&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 22 Apr 2013 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
        <link>http://gbradhopkins.com/mac/tutorials/2013/04/22/macheist-nanobundle-3.-10-well-spent.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://gbradhopkins.com/mac/tutorials/2013/04/22/macheist-nanobundle-3.-10-well-spent.html</guid>
        
        
        <category>Mac</category>
        
        <category>Tutorials</category>
        
      </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
